Gerlinde THEUNISSEN



CONTACT DETAILS

@ gerlinde.theunissen@gmail.com ⑤) + 41 77 284 0822 ☑ Schaffhauserstr. 123, 8057 Zurich

INTERESTS

Computational social science, urban econometrics.

SKILLS

Languages: German, English, Dutch, Spanish (full professional proficiency) | Danish, French (advanced) | Bulgarian (basic understanding).

Tools: Python, R, (Postgres) SQL, Git, Github, MEX, MarkDown, HTML, QGIS, Javascript, Microsoft Office.

Methods: Policy & project evaluation & analysis, Statistical data analysis, Causal inference, Research design, Spatial analysis, Machine learning & predictive analysis, Data management, Data visualization, Web applications & dashboards, Computational text & image analysis, Survey experiments.

ABOUT ME

28-year-old German-Dutch citizen permanently relocated to Zurich. In my free time, I run, hike, bike, swim, read novels, & learn Italian.

Volunteering Co-organizer of R-Users Zurich Meet-ups & statistic events for female PhDs at the University of Konstanz.

EXPERIENCE

DOCTORAL RESEARCHER | Excellenzcluster: 'The Politics of Inequality', University Konstanz. 2020 — Sep. 2024

- ♦ Focus on neighborhoods in the Global South, urban politics, political behavior.
- ♦ Collecting, managing, and analyzing various data sources (satellite imageries, administrative, survey, street networks, and other spatial data).
- Developing maps, dashboards, and other data visualizations.
- Independently organizing and managing research projects.
- ♦ Collaborating with other researchers and administrators to achieve projects on time within budget and with the data available.
- Publishing in academic journals and magazines and presenting findings at international conferences.

GUEST RESEARCHER | Institute for Political Science Zurich, University of Zurich. **2024**

GUEST RESEARCHER | Center for Comparative Immigration Studies, University of California, San Diego. **2023**

RESEARCH INTERN | 'GLOBAL CITIES' at CIDOB (Barcelona Centre for International Affairs), Barcelona, Spain.

⋄ Research on Covid policies and & writing of policy briefs for the municipality of Barcelona.

RESEARCH INTERN | 'GOVERNANCE AND FINANCIAL FLOWS' at Oxfam Novib, The Hague, Netherlands. **2018** — **2019**

 \diamond Research & writing reports on taxation focussing on Gender biases & the Global South.

INTERN | German Embassy, Sofia, Bulgaria.

2016 n preparation of

 \diamond Reports and briefs on corruption and emigration, preparation of speeches.

ASSISTANT | GERMAN CAMPAIGN TEAM at WeMove.eu. 2016 — 2018 Responsibility for the NGO's mail account, their German website, and organization of online and offline campaigns.

EDUCATION

DOCTORAL CANDIDATE. Graduate School of Behavioural Science (GSBS)

| University of Konstanz. 2020 — Dec. 2024 (Expected)

MASTER IN PUBLIC POLICY, POLITICAL ECONOMY AND DEVELOPMENT. Erasmus Mundus joint program | International Institute of Social Studies (ISS) at the Erasmus University Rotterdam, Institut Barcelona d'Estudis Internacionals (IBEI).

Bachelor in Politics and Public Administration. *University Konstanz.* **2014 – 2018**

SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

- ♦ Full scholarship for the Erasmus Mundus Joint Master Degree (EMJMD) |
 Erasmus+ Programme of the European Union.

 2018 2020
- ♦ Scholar of the German Academic Scholarship Foundation | Studienstiftung des Deutschen Volkes.
 2016 2020